<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Campus Lid Project on Office of Water Programs</title>
    <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Campus Lid Project on Office of Water Programs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 10:29:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:54:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/plants/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education and Outreach</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/education-and-outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:54:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/education-and-outreach/</guid>
      <description>Education and Outreach Campus LID Mobile Tour  &amp;nbsp;  This part of the project aimed to provide an opportunity for the public and stormwater professionals to see examples of how existing parking lots and streets can be retrofitted to include LID BMPs. Although retrofitting an existing urban space with new drainage systems presents many challenges, it also offers opportunities for improving the landscape. This tour lets you see these elements in a real-world setting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Construction</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:51:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/construction/</guid>
      <description>Construction Construction Log, December 7, 2015  The contractor will be returning to Calaveras Hall to clean up the disconnected downspouts, which are currently unpainted and have rough edges. The cleanup will include adding elbows to better direct&amp;hellip; Read more about the progress on December 7, 2015
Construction Log, September 25, 2015  The bioretention planters in Lots 7 and 10 and rain gardens along College Town Drive are complete, including vegetative cover, however extreme heat took its toll on several plants&amp;hellip; Read more about the progress on September 25, 2015</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning and Design</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/planning-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:51:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/planning-and-design/</guid>
      <description>Planning and Design Design Plans and Specs  Title page, campus overview, notes

 Calaveras Hall site plans

 Campus Grove site plans

 College Town Drive site plans

 Jed Smith Drive site plans

 Parking Lot 7 North site plans

 Parking Lot 7 South site plans

 Parking Lot 10 site plans

 Library Green site plans</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awards</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:51:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/awards/</guid>
      <description>Awards 2015 Urban Development Project of the Year—American Society of Civil Engineers, Sacramento Section  &amp;nbsp;  This award is quite an honor for OWP and its project partners. It recognizes the success of installing 25 LID best management practices (BMPs) devices in existing infrastructure on the Sacramento State campus and the further-reaching goal of demonstrating effective methods for regional stormwater management and sustainability. 
&amp;nbsp; 2016 CASQA BMP Implementation Project of the Year   The project was recognized because it is exemplary and unique in the quantity and types of LID BMPs implemented, the retrofit nature of the project, the cooperative effort among several stormwater organizations, and the significant environmental and social improvements it provides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:50:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring the LID Sites  Lot 7 Monitoring and Sampling  OWP conducted flow monitoring and sampling during 7 separate storm events, starting November 15, 2015 and continuing until March 12, 2016. At Lot 7, 3 out of the 6 total LID devices were monitored and sampled. Sampling and monitoring focused on total and dissolved metals, turbidity, total suspended solids, pesticides, temperature, and pH.
Lot 10 Monitoring and Sampling  Flow monitoring and sampling were also conducted at Lot 10 during 7 separate storm events from November 15, 2015 through March 12, 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional Lid</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/regional-lid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:50:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/regional-lid/</guid>
      <description>2015 Sacramento Regional LID Conference
Alumni Center
Wed, Nov 4, 2015 OWP and the American Basin Council of Watersheds (ABCW) hosted the fifth Sacramento Regional LID Conference on Nov 4, 2015 at the Sacramento State Alumni Center. The intent for this biannual conference is for local government, planners, designers, developers and environmental organizations to learn about strategies for integrating LID into sustainable community planning, design and construction. The 2015 event was successful with close to 200 attendees and topics included Regulatory Drivers for LID, Municipal Permit Compliance, and LID Implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Background</title>
      <link>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 11:39:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/featured-items/campus-lid-project/background/</guid>
      <description>Background Project Overview  In 2015, Sacramento State’s Office of Water Programs (OWP) and Facilities Management teamed with the City of Sacramento to install new stormwater management devices on campus. The devices, or low impact development best management practices (LID BMPs), reduce stormwater impacts to the American and Sacramento Rivers. Stormwater runoff from urban development is one of the leading contributors to water quality degradation.
LID is the sustainability term for managing stormwater; it involves treating runoff close to its source, incorporating existing infrastructure to optimize feasibility, and enhancing pollutant load reduction through stormwater infiltration, retention, and treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>