<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specialist Courses on Office of Water Programs</title>
    <link>/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Specialist Courses on Office of Water Programs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 16:47:27 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wastewater Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program</title>
      <link>/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/wastewater-treatment-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 16:48:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/wastewater-treatment-specialist/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
We offer two certificate programs for academic credit. Both the Wastewater Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program and the Water Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program are designed for operators and students interested in earning academic credit from a university that may be transferred to other colleges/universities. Registration requires university enrollment in Sacramento State&amp;rsquo;s College of Continuing Education.
If you are not planning to transfer your academic units to a college degree program, and are interested in earning continuing education units (CEUs), our other course offerings can meet your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program</title>
      <link>/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/water-treatment-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 16:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/operator-training/courses/specialist-courses/water-treatment-specialist/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
We offer two certificate programs for academic credit.Both the Water Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program and the Wastewater Treatment Plant Operation Specialist Certificate Program are designed for operators and students interested in earning academic credit from a university that may be transferred to other colleges/universities. Registration requires university enrollment in Sacramento State&amp;rsquo;s College of Continuing Education.
If you are not planning to transfer your academic units to a college degree program, and are interested in earning continuing education units (CEUs), our other course offerings can meet your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>