<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>University Connection on Office of Water Programs</title>
    <link>/university-connection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University Connection on Office of Water Programs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:22:39 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/university-connection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/university-connection/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:58:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/university-connection/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
OWP research engineers and scientists teach courses, lecture, and provide lab instruction in Sac State&amp;rsquo;s College of Engineering and Computer Science.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Assistants</title>
      <link>/university-connection/student-assistants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:58:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/university-connection/student-assistants/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
OWP has a long history of helping to train tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s future engineers and leaders. Students who worked at OWP have gone on to work at the US Army Corps of Engineers, Brown and Caldwell, CH2M Hill, and with other industry leaders.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regional San—SASD Graduate Fellowship Opportunities 2019</title>
      <link>/university-connection/srcsd-sasd-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:52:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/university-connection/srcsd-sasd-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Program Summary  The Sacramento Regional County Sanitation District (Regional San) and Sacramento Area Sewer District (SASD), in conjunction with the Office of Water Programs (OWP), are pleased to offer a Sacramento Regional County Sanitation District and Sacramento Area Sewer District Graduate Research Fellowship (hereafter referred to as the Regional San-SASD Fellowship) for students currently pursuing master&amp;rsquo;s degrees at California State University, Sacramento.
Regional San&amp;rsquo;s mission is to protect public health and the environment by conveying, treating, and recovering resources from wastewater responsibly and cost effectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OWP Fellowship Opportunities</title>
      <link>/university-connection/owp-fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 09:44:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/university-connection/owp-fellowship/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;
Program Summary  The Office of Water Programs (OWP) is pleased to offer a Graduate Research Fellowship for students currently pursuing master&amp;rsquo;s degrees at California State University, Sacramento. This Fellowship provides an opportunity for one or two students to fulfill their master&amp;rsquo;s project/thesis requirement by completing a research-based project in collaboration with OWP. Fellows will have the opportunity to work alongside faculty and research staff, and will be reimbursed for part-time tuition (up to 6 units) plus a one-time continuation fee (if needed) upon successful completion of the project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>