<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Office of Water Programs</title>
    <link>/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Office of Water Programs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 10:54:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tod Granicher</title>
      <link>/research/staff/tod-granicher/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 10:02:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/staff/tod-granicher/</guid>
      <description>Environmental Specialist Office of Water Programs, California State University, Sacramento, 2004–present
 Sampling and analytical quality assurance/control compliance Sample collection and analytical data methodology and interpretation Data review, storage, and retrieval Monitoring methodology and analytical data review OWP Water Quality Laboratory management Caltrans stormwater and monitoring equipment database management Software development for data retrieval and data management   Project Manager Sequoia Analytical Laboratories/Severn-Trent Laboratories, San Francisco, 1991–2003
 Analytical project design for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest environmental laboratory networks Customized sample-collection and analytical strategy development based on operational, contractual, and regulatory requirements of clients Technical consulting for clients across a wide multidisciplinary spectrum Project-specific method development in accordance with federal and state methodology and laboratory SOP Laboratory QA/QC compliance Laboratory data report design and production Client-directed laboratory services interpretation and training for non-experts   Professional Interests Analytical methodology and instrumentation; data quality control; environmental sample collection equipment and practices; database design, implementation, maintenance, and security</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Training</title>
      <link>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:40:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/training/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feasibility Studies</title>
      <link>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/feasibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:39:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/feasibility/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Evalution &amp; Statistical Analysis</title>
      <link>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/data-evalution/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:39:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/data-evalution/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Planning</title>
      <link>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/study-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:38:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/wastewater-treatment/study-planning/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Quality</title>
      <link>/research/reports/stormwater/water_quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:37:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/stormwater/water_quality/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring</title>
      <link>/research/reports/stormwater/monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:36:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/stormwater/monitoring/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Litter Management</title>
      <link>/research/reports/stormwater/litter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:36:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/stormwater/litter/</guid>
      <description>Study Quantifies Broom Sweeper Litter Pickup Ability Glenn Moeller and Gary Lippner Published in: American Sweeper (online magazine), Volume 8, 2000 Paper A Regression Model to Predict Litter in Urban Freeway Outfalls After Rainstorms Daniel B. Syrek, Masoud Kayhanian, and Scott Meyer Presented at: StormCon, Austin, Texas, July 2003 Paper | Abstract</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erosion</title>
      <link>/research/reports/stormwater/erosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:36:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/stormwater/erosion/</guid>
      <description>Evaluation of Storm Water Treatment by Vegetated Areas Adjacent to Highways Misty Scharff, Anna Lantin, and David Alderete Presented at: International Erosion Control Association (IECA), 34th Annual Conference and Expo, Las Vegas, Nevada, February 24–28, 2003 Paper | Abstract A GIS to Select Plant Species for Erosion Control Along California Highways Misty Scharff, Brent Hallock, S. Rein, and Michael Curto Presented at: International Erosion Control Association (IECA), Conference 33, Orlando, Florida, February 25–March 1, 2002 Paper | Abstract Plant Establishment with Rainfall Simulators for Erosion Control Misty Scharff, Brent Hallock, S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Managemet Practices</title>
      <link>/research/reports/stormwater/bmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 15:36:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/reports/stormwater/bmp/</guid>
      <description>Designing and Constructing Low Impact Development Stormwater Devices at Sacramento State Maureen Kerner Presented at:California State University, Sacramento, Santa Clara Hall, Room 1207, Sept 22, 2015 Presentation Retrofitting Low Impact Development (LID) for Stormwater at Sacramento State Kevin Murphy Presented at: 2015 CA Higher Education Sustainability Conference (CHESC) San Francisco, CA, May 20–24, 2015 Presentation Assessment Costs and Benefits of Detention for Water Quality Enhancement Scott M. Taylor, Laura Hansen, and Cathy Beitia Presented at: American Society of Civil Engineers World Water &amp;amp; Environmental Resources Congress 2001, Orlando, Florida, May 20–24, 2001 Abstract California Department of Transportation BMP Retrofit Pilot Program Brian Currier, Scott M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staff</title>
      <link>/research/staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:33:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/staff/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Tools</title>
      <link>/research/software-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:29:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/software-tools/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soils and Groundwater</title>
      <link>/research/soils-and-groundwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:29:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/soils-and-groundwater/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking Water and Wastewater</title>
      <link>/research/wastewater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 13:28:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/wastewater/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>